

Contact Me

- +917019363825
- abhijeetsaraf5665@gmail.co m

20th H Ashwini Layout, Ejipura Main Road, Koramangala, Bangalore

https://abhijeet65.github.io/ /Portfolio/

Bangalore, India

Social Profile

linkedin.com/in/abhijeet-saraf-123132139

Other Info

Skills

Springboot, Java, MERN,C, C++, Slackbots, Python, Docker & k8s, React, Angular and Machine Learning

Awards

1. Recieved 6 Blue Awards from

ABHIJEET SARAF

Cloud Engineer



About Me

Motivated cloud engineer with 2+ years of experience in building scalable automation tools by revamping process efficiency. I am seeking a company where I can use my experience and skills to help the company meet and surpass its goals.



Experience

1-OCT-2020 -Present American Express | Cloud Solutions Engineer

Responsible for Collaborating with different application teams, developers, engineers, and project managers to provide the best design solutions and suggest appropriate systems based on the code or applications. Which also includes managing private cloud PAAS, CI/CD, development to support platform, migration automation and self-service offerings.

_{15-Jan-2020 - 18-} American Express | Technology Intern Analyst July-2020

Worked on virtual payments system wherein i have enabled the application to work with different timezones. Used spring MVC framework and Java.

June-2018 -August-2018 Onibus Technologies Pvt Ltd. | Software Developer Intern

During my internship here, I was working on project using MEAN Stack. My work is to develop customized parent and student dashboards. I worked on the front-end side & optimal search and retrieval from back-end.



American Express colleagues and leadership for appreciation of my work.

2. Certificate of appreciation from codechef for volunteering in competitive programming workshop as a instructor.
3. Rank 1 in competitive coding competition held in an IOS development workshop.

Languages

English, Hindi

Interest

Music, Travelling, Chess, Trekking

Education

2016 - 2020

Ramaiah Institute Of Technology | B.E. Information Science And Engineering

CGPA - 9.16

2014 - 2015

DAV Public School | Intermediate 10+2

91.6%



Projects

American Express | Profile Scanner

Automation suite to reduce the turnaround time and increase productivity by 80% by revamping the processes of firewall recreation in new openshift clusters.

American Express | CertaasBot

Slackbot which helps the user to trigger the certificate migration through the interactive interface of slackbot app. It uses socketmode and integrated with cloud automation APIs to submit and process cert migration requests.

American Express | Cognitive-UI

Intelligent UI which learns from the user activity on the website. Next time login it gives recommendations to users to visit different parts of the UI based on trained machine learning models.

Ramaiah Institute Of Technology | IPL-Match-predictor

Machine Learning Project for predicting the winner of matches and winner of the series of IPL matches played .We were using classification algorithms and lot of data pre-processing and feature extraction on data of team members of each team to get a final prediction accurately.Also,we have trained and tested our model on various ML algorithms

Ramaiah Institute Of Technology | Supermarket Billing System

Swings, JSP and MySQL database based for real-time billing of products in supermarket. Also Admin can add, delete or modify the users, products and stock in the supermarket. Separate Login for cashier and admins with access privileges.